# NADEZHDA ZABORSKAIA

## DATA SCIENTIST



### **Contact Info**

22763, Hamburg

+49 176 301 40881

zaborskaiang@gmail.com

www.nazabo.com

#### Skills

Python, R, SQL (PrestoDB, HiveQL)

Mathematical statistics (NumPy, Pandas, SciPy)

Machine Learning Algorithms (Scikit-learn, Tensorflow)

Image processing (OpenCV)

Data mining, EDA, Data visualisation (Matplotlib, Seaborn, Plotly, Folium, OSMnx)

Data scrapping (request), Data Storage (Amazon S3)

GitHub, GitLab, MIFlow

Communication and presentation skills, Team player

## Languages

Russian (native) English (advanced) German (elementary)

#### **Interests**

My discussion club: www.sofatalks.club, self-education via online courses, traveling and fixing mobile gadgets

## Objective

I am a highly motivated and curious data scientist, specialising in Machine Learning and statistical methods in data analysis. Problem solving is my creed. I am interested in new technologies and in their application to improve business processes.

#### Education

M.Sc. Management and Data Science

October 2016 - March 2020

Leuphana University of Lüneburg, Germany

M.Sc. Economics and Finance

October 2007 - June 2013

Moscow State University Of Railway Engineering, Russia

## Experience

• Data Scientist (working student), FREE NOW (formerly mytaxi)
Hamburg, Germany

January 2019 - May 2020

Worked on Customer Lifetime Value prediction project with application of different Machine Learning techniques in MIFlow, using customer behaviour data. Optimised Python code in PySpark for city simulation project. Performed city analysis for UX team, using osmnx package for geospatial data visualisation, building infographics. Participated in technical meetings with presentation of results and discussion.

#### Financial Specialist, Mosgortrans

Moscow, Russia

August 2010 - August 2015

Financial analysis and payroll financing in SAP enterprise software. Economic cost planning of the Mosgortrans network (40 enterprises) and calculation of important KPIs of the company for accounting department. Working with a cash account, analysing the daily balance for control cash flows and reporting. Preparation of the annual and semi-annual financial statements for CEO.